**Apartment List Privacy Policy**
=================================

Updated and last reviewed as of: July 1, 2024.  
  
Welcome to our website, [www.apartmentlist.com](http://www.apartmentlist.com/), and our related mobile applications (“**Site**”) as operated by Apartment List, Inc. (the “**Company**” or “**we**” or “**us**”).

**Scope**

This privacy policy describes what personal information we collect, how we collect, use, and disclose it, as well as tools available to you to manage your privacy, and your rights.

We operate the Site and other associated services and offerings which:

* allow companies to list apartments, houses or other real estate for rent or sale,
* provide artificial intelligence (“**AI**”) leasing assistant services (“**LEA**”) to the above companies’ renters and prospective renters, and
* allow individuals to locate apartments, houses or other real estate for rent or sale (collectively with the Site, the “**Services**”).

We make our Services available to individuals subject to this privacy policy and the Terms of Use. If you do not want personal information about you to be used in the manner described in this privacy policy, please do not use the Services.

This privacy policy applies to your personal information that:

* you provide to us, including when you register on the Site to view properties for rent and when you communicate with our AI leasing assistant (including via phone, email, text message, chat message, and other electronic communications),
* we receive when you send us emails, text messages, and other electronic communications,
* we learn from you when you access or use the Services and our social media pages such as Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, LinkedIn, and YouTube,
* we receive from our business customers (for example, property management companies which list properties on our Site or which use our AI leasing assistant services) and our business customers’ service providers, and
* we learn when you interact with our advertisements that are displayed on other websites or applications.

This privacy policy does not cover, and we are not responsible for the privacy, data or other practices of any of our business customers (for example, property management companies and their service providers) or third parties (except as required by applicable law). See “[Third Parties](https://www.apartmentlist.com/about/privacy#third-parties)” below for more information.

**Specific US Notices:** If you are a resident of California, Colorado, Connecticut, Delaware, Iowa, Montana, Nebraska, New Hampshire, New Jersey, Oregon, Texas, Virginia, or Utah, please see your additional rights and our additional disclosures under the sections titled “[Privacy Notice for Certain US Residents](https://www.apartmentlist.com/about/privacy#certain-us-residents)” and if you are a California resident, see also: [“California’s Shine the Light Law”](https://www.apartmentlist.com/about/privacy#certain-us-residents).

**California Apartment List Workforce:** If you are a resident of California and you are an employee, job applicant, controlling owner, director, officer, independent contractor, or medical staff of Apartment List, please see our disclosures under the section titled “[Privacy Notice for California Company Resources](https://www.apartmentlist.com/about/privacy#certain-us-residents)[.](https://www.apartmentlist.com/about/privacy#Privacy-Notice-for-California-Company-Resources)”

### **User Consents**

**_Apartment List Users:_** 

**By using and accessing the Services, you consent to the practices described in this privacy policy and you represent that you are at least 18 years old and located in the United States.**

**By registering as a user of our Services, you consent to us texting you in order to download our mobile app when you register, when you forget your password, and for transactional messages related to your account. In addition, by choosing to contact a property, you give our business customers (e.g., property managers and landlords) your express written consent to calling and texting you about any inquiries you submit through our Services, including by calling and texting you via automated means and pre-recorded or artificial voices, even if you are on a do-not-call list.** 

**_LEA Users:_**

**When you communicate with our business customers and are notified that an “artificial intelligence” (AI) assistant is available to answer your questions, you understand that you are interacting with an AI bot and not a human. By continuing to interact with our AI leasing assistant, you consent to the practices described in this privacy policy and you represent that you are at least 18 years old and located in the United States.**

**By interacting with our AI leasing assistant, you consent to us calling, emailing and texting you and web chatting with you and otherwise communicating with you. In addition, by choosing to contact a property, you give our business customers (e.g., property managers and landlords) your express written consent to calling and texting you (either directly or through our AI leasing assistant services) about any inquiries you submit through our AI leasing assistants, including by calling and texting you via automated means and pre-recorded or artificial voices, even if you are on a do-not-call list. Consent is not a condition of purchase. Your use of and access to our AI leasing assistant acts as your binding electronic signature. Message rates and data charges may apply. Carriers are not liable for delayed or undelivered messages. If you have any questions about your text or data plan, it is best to contact your carrier.**

**_All Users:_**

**Consent is not a condition of purchase. Your use of and access to our Service acts as your binding electronic signature. Message rates and data charges may apply. Carriers are not liable for delayed or undelivered messages. If you have any questions about your text or data plan, it is best to contact your carrier.**

**You may stop receiving calls or cancel receiving text messages from us at any time. To stop receiving calls or cancel messages received from property managers or landlords, you must contact them directly. To stop receiving calls, you may tell us verbally on the call. To stop receiving text messages from us, just text “STOP” in response to a text message. After you send a text message “STOP” to us, we will send you a text message to confirm that you have been unsubscribed. After this, you will no longer receive text messages from us. If you want to receive text messages from us again, you can email us at** [**support@apartmentlist.com**](mailto:support@apartmentlist.com) **or respond to our last text message with a keyword such as “START” or “YES.” If you are experiencing issues with the text messaging program, you can reply with the keyword “HELP” for more assistance, or you can get help directly at** [**support@apartmentlist.com**](mailto:support@apartmentlist.com)**.**

**What do we mean by personal information?**

When we use the term “personal information” in this Privacy Notice, we mean information that identifies, relates to, describes, is reasonably capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, to an individual or household. It does not include deidentified information that is maintained in a form that is not capable of being associated with or reasonably linked to an individual.

**Changes and Updates to this Privacy Policy**

We may update this privacy policy at any time. When we do, we will also revise the date on this privacy policy. Where required by law, we will notify you or obtain your consent to make these changes. Your continued use of or access to the Service constitutes your agreement to this privacy policy and any updates.

**Users Must Be At Least 18**

Our Service is not intended for individuals under 18 years of age. If you are under 18, do not provide or use any information on this Service. We delete information of people under 18 when we learn that we have collected personal information from them. Please contact us at [privacy@apartmentlist.com](mailto:privacy@apartmentlist.com) if you believe that we have information about a person under 18.

**United States Users Only**

Our Service is intended for individuals located in the United States only. You are not authorized to use the Service if you are located outside the United States. If you continue to use the Services without authorization from outside the United States, then the information collected through the Services will be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States or other countries in which we, our service providers, and third party partners operate. Your consent to this privacy policy represents your consent to such transfer, storage and processing outside of your country of residence, which may have different data protection rules than those of your country of residence.

When we determine that a user of our Services is located outside the United States, we delete such user’s personal information from our systems.

### **Personal Information Collected**

**User-Provided Information.** You may provide information to the Company when you register, log in, or use the Service, including when you request access to our Service via our service providers, such as via the Facebook marketplace, or when you call, email, text, or otherwise send electronic messages to us through our AI leasing assistant. You may also provide information to us in your capacity as a business professional (e.g., an employee of one of our existing or prospective business customers or vendors). 

The information you may provide includes your: 

* name, 
* social media name, 
* email address, 
* telephone number,
* income range, 
* eviction history,
* property search (for example, apartment with two bedrooms in a particular city), 
* physical address (for example, when you participate in our sweepstakes or other promotions, when you provide feedback, or when you apply for housing during a disaster), 
* gender and other demographic information, 
* feedback about our Service, 
* job applicant-related information, and
* status as an existing renter or prospective renter of one of our property management companies.  

You also provide us information when you send us emails, text messages, chat messages via our Service, or other electronic messages, or when you participate in one of our online sweepstakes or apply for a job through our online Careers page. 

Any time you enter information into a form or other data entry field available on the Service or send us an electronic message, the Company collects and stores that information for our business use. Please do not disclose to us any sensitive information. Some of the information you may provide is optional. However, if you elect not to provide such information, you may not be able to access the information you had requested to access or use or you may not be able to use the Service.

**Information Provided by our Business Customers and their Vendors.** Our business customers (for example, property management companies) provide us with reports showing which individuals have moved into their properties (i.e., move-in data). You may be listed as one of their tenants in those reports. The report may show the following:

* your contact information including name, email address, phone number, physical address,
* the date you moved into our business customer’s property,
* the date the individual became a potential customer of business customer in business customer’s system,
* the resident and lead identification numbers created by the business customer, and other information that the business customer deems related to the service that we provide to the business customer, and
* the name of the third party company that was the source of the individual that converted into a resident at one of the business customer’s properties (for example, if you first saw a property on our Site, then we would be the source).

Our business customers may also use our leasing agent services and integrate their property management software with our leasing agent workflows so that we can provide AI leasing assistant services to their renters and prospective renters. Through this relationship we receive renter data, prospective renter data, and contact information so that we can help respond to renter and prospective renter inquiries. Sometimes we receive this information from our business customers’ vendors.

**Automatically Collected Information and Cookies.** When you visit the Service or open one of our HTML emails or interact with our social media pages, certain information from your web browser, mobile device or mobile identifier, IP address, cookies, or email may be recorded through the use of different types of technology, including clear gifs, web beacons, and cookies. See “[**Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**](https://www.apartmentlist.com/about/privacy#third-parties)” below. This automatically collected information may include the following:

* unique identification numbers, such as your user identification number for our Service, your IP address (Internet Protocol address) and your location derived from IP address,
* mobile device type and mobile device identifier,
* web browser type,
* the web pages or sites that you visit just before or after the Service,
* the pages you view,
* the dates and times that you use the Service,
* information about interactions with our emails, and
* information about properties you may be interested in.

We also allow analytics companies (for example, Google Analytics) to use tracking technologies to collect information automatically about our users’ computers or mobile devices and their online activities.

**Logging in via Google or Facebook.** You may be given the option to access or register for the Service through the use of your user name and passwords for certain services provided by third parties, such as Google or Facebook account credentials, or you may otherwise have the option to authorize third parties to provide personal information or other information to us. By authorizing us to connect with Google, Facebook or other third parties, you authorize us to access and store your name, email address(es), education, profile pictures, interests and activities, your gender and age, your hometown, school, employer, your username and other information that Google, Facebook or other third parties make available to us, and to use and disclose any such information in accordance with this privacy policy. You should check your privacy settings in your Google, Facebook and other third party account to understand and change the information that they can send to us. Please review their terms of use and privacy policies carefully before using their services and connecting to our Service.

**Information from Interactions with Ads.** We advertise our Services on other websites and applications. When you interact with our advertisements (for example, you view or click on an advertisement), we receive information about that interaction to help us provide our Services to you.

**Location Information.** Some of the features of the Service may enable or require us to access information about your location (“**Location-based Services**”). In order to use Location-based Services, you must allow the Company to access your localized position through your mobile device, which the Company may accomplish through a variety of means, including IP address, or geo-fencing technology, as available. Your mobile device may automatically enable the provision of some Location-based Services, but you will have the option to enable or disable such Location-based Services at any time by configuring your mobile device’s setting appropriately. See “**Your Choices and Opting Out**” below.

**Information from Other Sources.** If we combine or associate information from other sources with personal information that we collect through the Service, we will treat the combined information as personal information in accordance with this privacy policy.

**Aggregated Data.** Aggregated data is data we collect about a group or category of features, services or individuals, from which individual identities have been removed. For example, information about how you use a feature may be collected and combined with information about how others use the same feature, without any personal information included in the resulting data.

### **Uses of Your Personal Information**

We use your information for these purposes:

**Providing and Supporting the Service.** The Company uses your information to provide to you all of the features and services found on the Service and to connect you with our business customers and other third parties upon your request. We will use your email address for non-marketing or administrative purposes such as notifying you of major Service updates, responding to your requests, contacting winners of our sweepstakes, and sending you other types of notices. We may also use your information to diagnose and fix server problems. We may use your information to process your job application and to contact you about a job. In addition, we may review the content of communications you make through the Service so that we can provide better services. For example, monitoring user communications may help us identify and remove users who are attempting to scam other users or perform other illegal activity.

**Managing our Relationships with Business Customers and Other Businesses.** We use the reporting information provided by our business customers (i.e., move-in data) in order to match their customers (i.e., renters) against our users. If we are the source of a business transaction, then we charge our business customer a fee. For example, if you saw a property on our Site for the first time and later signed a lease for that property, then our business customer who manages that property would pay us a fee because we were the original source of that transaction. We may also use the move-in data provided by our business customers for audit purposes and to exercise our rights and defenses with respect to our business customers. If an individual included in the move-in data from a business customer has not used our Service, we delete that individual’s information. We also use renter data and contact information to provide our leasing agent services (e.g., answering your calls or responding to text messages with your inquiries).

When we use contact information of the professionals who work for our business customers, vendors, or other businesses, we use the information to facilitate the business relationship with the companies.

**Improving the Service.** The Company may use the information that we collect to understand usage trends and preferences, to improve the way the Service works and looks, to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, and to create new features and functionality. We may also track your use of the Services to improve the design and functionality of the Services. Our AI leasing assistant will create computer-generated transcripts of your requests which are used to help the AI leasing assistant understand you better and recognize what you say.

**Customizing your Experience.** The Company may use your information to remember you when you return to our Site (for example, with cookies) or when you contact us again through a business customer so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the Site. We may also use your information to provide you with custom, personalized advertisements, content and information through the use of cookies. For example, based on your property preferences, we may tailor the search results that you see on our Service. The Company also uses the location information that you provide or that it collects from your mobile device or IP address, to show you properties that may be of interest to you.

**Analyzing the Service.** The Company may use your information to: (a) monitor aggregate usage metrics such as total number of users and number and type of pages viewed, (b) track conversion of prospective renters into actual renters of our business customers, (c) perform fraud monitoring and prevention and security, and (d) determining the effectiveness of our Service.

**Marketing the Service.** Where permitted by applicable law, the Company may use your email address or other personal contact information to send you promotional or marketing messages relating to the Service, which you will have the ability to opt-out of. We use your information to monitor the effectiveness of these promotional and marketing campaigns.

**Third Party Uses.** We may partner with certain third parties to collect other information to engage in analysis, research, and reporting of Service usage patterns. While we endeavor to limit their activities to those of a service provider (e.g., selecting restricted or limited data processing) these third parties may deliver advertising to you on other websites and applications, based on your activity on our website and other websites over time. These third parties may set and access cookies on your computer or other devices and may also use web logs or web beacons. See “**Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**” and see “**Your Choices and Opting Out**” to opt out of interest-based advertising by third parties from cookies.

**Evaluating a Combination.** We may use your information as part of evaluating a merger, acquisition, debt financing, or sale of Company assets, as well as in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership.

**Combining Information.** We may combine information from the Services that is linked or reasonably linked to a particular computer or device with personal information. If we combine such information with personal information, the combined information will be treated by us as personal information as long as it is combined.

**General and Legal Uses.** We may use your information if we believe it is appropriate or necessary: (a) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and that of you and others; (b) to prevent or stop activity we may consider to be, or is at risk of being, illegal, unethical or legally actionable activity; (c) to protect our operations and the security of our Services; (d) under applicable law; (e) to comply with legal process and our legal obligations; (f) to respond to requests or requirements from public, law and government authorities (including national security and law enforcement requirements) and private parties; (g) to enforce our terms and conditions; and (h) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

**With Consent**. We may use your personal information in other ways with your consent or at your direction.

‍
